<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Walker Harrison</title>
    <link>https://walker-harrison.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Walker Harrison</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 26 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://walker-harrison.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Pushing Google&#39;s Autocorrect to the Limit</title>
      <link>https://walker-harrison.com/posts/2020-12-17-pushing-google-s-autocorrect-to-the-limit/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://walker-harrison.com/posts/2020-12-17-pushing-google-s-autocorrect-to-the-limit/</guid>
      <description>I only had a vague understanding of the word “endocrinology” when it popped up in a recent article, so I Googled it. Or at least, I tried to. Instead I typed “wndicromoly,” and was disappointed by the results, all due respect to Wendy Cromwell:
  My expectation was that Google would either automatically redirect me to the right results or at least politely ask, “Did I mean: endocrinology?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About Me!</title>
      <link>https://walker-harrison.com/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://walker-harrison.com/about/</guid>
      <description>Hello! My name is Walker Harrison and I&amp;rsquo;m a data scientist.
I graduated from Columbia University in 2014 with a double major in mathematics and creative writing. After working in marketing and business development roles for several years at IBM and The Practical Dev, I got my Master&amp;rsquo;s degree in statistics from Duke University. Since 2018 I have been working as a quantitative analyst for the New York Yankees.
This website will be used primarily to publish blogposts that explore some of the ways statistics intersect with our everyday lives.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Consulting</title>
      <link>https://walker-harrison.com/consulting/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://walker-harrison.com/consulting/</guid>
      <description>If you or your company need assistance somewhere along the data analysis pipeline, I may be a good fit.
I have experience in data extraction and retrieval, including web scraping of both static and dynamic content. I am well versed in SQL and have set up relational databases for various personal projects, including ones that required &amp;ldquo;big data.&amp;rdquo; I do most of my data cleaning and manipulation in R, and enjoy helping others wrangle their data via Stack Overflow questions.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
